Md. Sayed Ahammed

■ 01771224089 🖾 <u>sayed@sayedahammed.me</u> 🖬 sayed-ahammed 🗘 sayedahammed ⊕ sayedahammed.me

CAREER SUMMARY

An ambitious and passionate software engineer with a strong academic background in BSc. in CSE. With analytical and problem-solving abilities, Sayed actively contribute to business digitalization through various software development technologies. Sayed have 7+ years' experience in software development, including frontend development, backend development. Seeking opportunities to contribute to dynamic software development environment.

SKILLS

Software Engineering Requirement Analysis, System & Database Design

Programming Languages
Web Technologies
HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
Frameworks & Tools
Spring Boot, Spring Soc

Frameworks & Tools Spring Boot, Spring Security, Spring Batch
Core Concepts Object-Oriented Programming, Multi-threading,

Asynchronous Processing

EXPERIENCE

RedDot Digital Ltd.

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Software Engineer March 2020 - Present

- Implemented various features for the Enterprise CRM solution, including a number activation service that activates more than 1 million numbers per year, improved efficiency using asynchronous processing.
- ▶ Built scalable Lead Management & TT Portal Solution using React and Spring Boot, that facilitates smooth business solution. Contributed to seamless business digitization.
- ▶ Implemented Top-Up Service for MFS Wallet using Java, Spring Boot, JavaScript, PostgreSQL and integrated Payment Gateway that increased revenue and designed system that increased success rate significantly.
- ▶ Designed and implemented middleware for mobile applications, integrating Java Security JWT token for robust authentication and authorization.
- Integrated and developed offline and online billing services, ensuring seamless transaction processing and system reliability.
- ▶ Developed a server health monitoring system with real-time alerts via email and SMS to ensure proactive issue resolution and system reliability.
- Implemented a paper eKYC system to streamline verification processes and reduce daily operational workload.
- ▶ Developed an HRBP feedback system integrated with a chatbot, streamlining feedback collection via email and improving HR efficiency.

Genex Digital Dhaka, Bangladesh

Developer, Software Development

June 2019 - March 2020

- Design and develop Chatbot Platform with Relational and NoSQL databases, integrating various platforms (Facebook Graph API, Viber REST API, WhatsApp Business API) to build chatbots that can respond to customer queries, payment, send notifications, and more.
- Developed AI-powered chatbots for telecom, banking, and FAQ automation, enhancing customer engagement and service efficiency.

Preneur Lab Limited Dhaka, Bangladesh

Back-end Developer

January 2018 - June 2019

• Requirement gathering to implement and deploy custom Chatbot Solutions for Giant Telecom Companies that contributed to earn significant revenue in Data Purchase with conversational chatbot.

- Integrated VAS services, payment service gateway, and data purchase, enhance user experience and enable seamless digital transactions.
- ▶ Increased user retention by 40% by push notification, exciting offer, and re-train feature.
- Developed a selfie-sharing campaign with automatic location collection, driving high user engagement and interactive participation.

EDUCATION

Daffodil International University

BSc, Computer Science and Engineering

Dhaka, Bangladesh

2013 - 2017